export interface Question {
    id: number;
    idQuiz: number;
    point: number;
    question: string;
    answers: string[];
    writeAnswer: string;
  }
  
  export const questions: Question[] = [
    {
      id: 1,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "What is 3D modeling?",
      answers: ["Creating 2D images", "Developing a mathematical representation", "Sketching", "Sculpting"],
      writeAnswer: "Developing a mathematical representation",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "Which software is commonly used for 3D modeling?",
      answers: ["Photoshop", "Blender", "Microsoft Word", "Illustrator"],
      writeAnswer: "Blender",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "What file format is typically used to export 3D models?",
      answers: ["JPEG", "OBJ", "PDF", "TXT"],
      writeAnswer: "OBJ",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "Which technique is used to create 3D textures?",
      answers: ["UV mapping", "Drawing", "Painting", "Filming"],
      writeAnswer: "UV mapping",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "What is the process of creating a wireframe for a 3D model called?",
      answers: ["Rigging", "Texturing", "Modeling", "Sketching"],
      writeAnswer: "Modeling",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "Which of the following is a method for animating 3D models?",
      answers: ["Rigging", "Rendering", "Retouching", "Recording"],
      writeAnswer: "Rigging",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "What is the term for the realistic rendering of light and shadows in 3D modeling?",
      answers: ["Texturing", "Ray tracing", "Sculpting", "Shading"],
      writeAnswer: "Ray tracing",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "What is the purpose of a 3D rendering engine?",
      answers: ["Animating models", "Drawing sketches", "Exporting files", "Generating images from models"],
      writeAnswer: "Generating images from models",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "What is the term for the process of making a 3D model ready for animation?",
      answers: ["Texturing", "Rigging", "Modeling", "Mapping"],
      writeAnswer: "Rigging",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      idQuiz: 1,
      point: 2,
      question: "Which file format is often used for 3D printing?",
      answers: ["STL", "JPEG", "PNG", "PDF"],
      writeAnswer: "STL",
    },
    {
        id: 11,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the primary purpose of graphic design?",
        answers: ["To write code", "To create visual content", "To manage finances", "To develop apps"],
        writeAnswer: "To create visual content",
      },
      {
        id: 12,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which software is commonly used for graphic design?",
        answers: ["AutoCAD", "Excel", "Photoshop", "Blender"],
        writeAnswer: "Photoshop",
      },
      {
        id: 13,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the term for the arrangement of elements in a design?",
        answers: ["Coding", "Layout", "Scripting", "Texturing"],
        writeAnswer: "Layout",
      },
      {
        id: 14,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which of the following is a vector graphics editor?",
        answers: ["Photoshop", "Illustrator", "Word", "Premiere Pro"],
        writeAnswer: "Illustrator",
      },
      {
        id: 15,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the process of combining text and graphics called?",
        answers: ["Typesetting", "Editing", "Rendering", "Programming"],
        writeAnswer: "Typesetting",
      },
      {
        id: 16,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which color model is used for print design?",
        answers: ["RGB", "CMYK", "HEX", "HSB"],
        writeAnswer: "CMYK",
      },
      {
        id: 17,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the term for the space around and between elements in a design?",
        answers: ["Margin", "Gutter", "Padding", "Whitespace"],
        writeAnswer: "Whitespace",
      },
      {
        id: 18,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which of the following is an example of a serif font?",
        answers: ["Arial", "Helvetica", "Times New Roman", "Verdana"],
        writeAnswer: "Times New Roman",
      },
      {
        id: 19,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the principle of creating a sense of movement in a design called?",
        answers: ["Balance", "Rhythm", "Contrast", "Emphasis"],
        writeAnswer: "Rhythm",
      },
      {
        id: 20,
        idQuiz:3,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the term for adjusting the space between characters in a word?",
        answers: ["Leading", "Kerning", "Tracking", "Spacing"],
        writeAnswer: "Kerning",
      },
      {
        id: 21,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does HTML stand for?",
        answers: ["Hyper Text Markup Language", "Home Tool Markup Language", "Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language", "Hyper Tool Markup Language"],
        writeAnswer: "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      },
      {
        id: 22,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which tag is used to define an internal style sheet in HTML?",
        answers: ["<style>", "<script>", "<link>", "<meta>"],
        writeAnswer: "<style>",
      },
      {
        id: 23,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which programming language is not used for front-end web development?",
        answers: ["JavaScript", "Python", "HTML", "CSS"],
        writeAnswer: "Python",
      },
      {
        id: 24,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which CSS property controls the spacing between lines of text?",
        answers: ["line-height", "font-spacing", "text-spacing", "line-spacing"],
        writeAnswer: "line-height",
      },
      {
        id: 25,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of JavaScript?",
        answers: ["To style web pages", "To create database queries", "To add interactivity to web pages", "To create web server configurations"],
        writeAnswer: "To add interactivity to web pages",
      },
      {
        id: 26,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which event occurs when the user clicks on an HTML element?",
        answers: ["onchange", "onclick", "onmouseover", "onmouseclick"],
        writeAnswer: "onclick",
      },
      {
        id: 27,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does CSS stand for?",
        answers: ["Creative Style Sheets", "Cascading Style Sheets", "Computer Style Sheets", "Colorful Style Sheets"],
        writeAnswer: "Cascading Style Sheets",
      },
      {
        id: 28,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which HTML tag is used to define navigation links?",
        answers: ["<nav>", "<link>", "<a>", "<section>"],
        writeAnswer: "<a>",
      },
      {
        id: 29,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is a responsive web design?",
        answers: ["A design that reacts to user interactions", "A design that adapts to different screen sizes", "A design that uses artificial intelligence", "A design that allows real-time updates"],
        writeAnswer: "A design that adapts to different screen sizes",
      },
      {
        id: 30,
       idQuiz:5,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which programming language is used for server-side web development?",
        answers: ["Java", "JavaScript", "HTML", "CSS"],
        writeAnswer: "Java",
      },
      {
        id: 31,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does SEO stand for?",
        answers: ["Search Engine Optimization", "Search Engine Operation", "Search Engine Openness", "Search Engine Opportunity"],
        writeAnswer: "Search Engine Optimization",
      },
      {
        id: 32,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of a meta description tag in SEO?",
        answers: ["To add images to web pages", "To define the page content for search engines", "To create links between web pages", "To embed videos on web pages"],
        writeAnswer: "To define the page content for search engines",
      },
      {
        id: 33,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the goal of email marketing?",
        answers: ["To increase website traffic", "To improve search engine rankings", "To create interactive web pages", "To send spam emails"],
        writeAnswer: "To increase website traffic",
      },
      {
        id: 34,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of a call-to-action (CTA) in marketing?",
        answers: ["To track user behavior", "To improve email deliverability", "To encourage user interaction", "To measure social media engagement"],
        writeAnswer: "To encourage user interaction",
      },
      {
        id: 35,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the key benefit of using social media in marketing?",
        answers: ["To create automated marketing campaigns", "To share personal stories", "To increase brand visibility", "To generate email leads"],
        writeAnswer: "To increase brand visibility",
      },
      {
        id: 36,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which metric measures the effectiveness of SEO efforts?",
        answers: ["Click-through rate (CTR)", "Cost per click (CPC)", "Return on investment (ROI)", "Email open rate"],
        writeAnswer: "Click-through rate (CTR)",
      },
      {
        id: 37,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of keyword research in SEO?",
        answers: ["To optimize website performance", "To increase website loading speed", "To reduce bounce rate", "To improve website security"],
        writeAnswer: "To optimize website performance",
      },
      {
        id: 38,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which factor is crucial for local SEO?",
        answers: ["Quality content", "Mobile-friendly design", "Google My Business listing", "Paid advertising campaigns"],
        writeAnswer: "Google My Business listing",
      },
      {
        id: 39,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of backlinks in SEO?",
        answers: ["To increase website traffic", "To optimize website images", "To monitor website performance", "To improve website navigation"],
        writeAnswer: "To increase website traffic",
      },
      {
        id: 40,
        idQuiz:7,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the primary goal of content marketing?",
        answers: ["To analyze competitor websites", "To create engaging content", "To update website databases", "To automate social media posts"],
        writeAnswer: "To create engaging content",
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of financial statements?",
        answers: ["To manage employee salaries", "To calculate income taxes", "To communicate financial information", "To process credit card payments"],
        writeAnswer: "To communicate financial information",
      },
      {
        id: 42,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the difference between assets and liabilities?",
        answers: ["Assets are money owed, liabilities are possessions", "Assets are debts, liabilities are gains", "Assets are resources owned, liabilities are debts owed", "Assets are investments, liabilities are expenses"],
        writeAnswer: "Assets are resources owned, liabilities are debts owed",
      },
      {
        id: 43,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does ROI stand for in financial terms?",
        answers: ["Return on Investment", "Risk of Inflation", "Revenue Over Interest", "Rate of Income"],
        writeAnswer: "Return on Investment",
      },
      {
        id: 44,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of budgeting in finance?",
        answers: ["To increase profits", "To decrease expenses", "To manage cash flow", "To avoid financial reporting"],
        writeAnswer: "To manage cash flow",
      },
      {
        id: 45,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which financial statement shows a company's profitability over a period?",
        answers: ["Balance Sheet", "Income Statement", "Cash Flow Statement", "Retained Earnings Statement"],
        writeAnswer: "Income Statement",
      },
      {
        id: 46,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the role of an auditor in financial auditing?",
        answers: ["To prepare financial reports", "To analyze market trends", "To verify financial records", "To forecast future earnings"],
        writeAnswer: "To verify financial records",
      },
      {
        id: 47,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of GAAP (Generally Accepted Accounting Principles)?",
        answers: ["To regulate global financial markets", "To standardize financial reporting", "To provide tax exemptions", "To enforce corporate governance"],
        writeAnswer: "To standardize financial reporting",
      },
      {
        id: 48,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does FIFO (First In, First Out) refer to in inventory accounting?",
        answers: ["An investment strategy", "A financial fraud detection method", "A cost allocation method", "An inventory valuation method"],
        writeAnswer: "An inventory valuation method",
      },
      {
        id: 49,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of financial forecasting?",
        answers: ["To predict market volatility", "To determine production quotas", "To estimate future financial performance", "To assess employee productivity"],
        writeAnswer: "To estimate future financial performance",
      },
      {
        id: 50,
        idQuiz:9,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which financial ratio measures a company's ability to pay short-term debts?",
        answers: ["Current Ratio", "Debt-to-Equity Ratio", "Return on Assets", "Earnings per Share"],
        writeAnswer: "Current Ratio",
      },
      {
        id: 51,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does SMART stand for in goal setting?",
        answers: ["Specific, Measurable, Achievable, Relevant, Timely", "Strong, Meaningful, Attainable, Realistic, Targeted", "Strategic, Managed, Achievable, Resolute, Time-bound", "Structured, Measured, Accountable, Reasonable, Targeted"],
        writeAnswer: "Specific, Measurable, Achievable, Relevant, Timely",
      },
      {
        id: 52,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of time management?",
        answers: ["To increase productivity", "To reduce stress", "To prioritize tasks", "To schedule meetings"],
        writeAnswer: "To increase productivity",
      },
      {
        id: 53,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the concept of growth mindset?",
        answers: ["Belief that abilities can be developed through dedication and hard work", "Belief that intelligence is fixed and cannot change", "Belief that success is determined by luck", "Belief that talent alone leads to success"],
        writeAnswer: "Belief that abilities can be developed through dedication and hard work",
      },
      {
        id: 54,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are soft skills in personal development?",
        answers: ["Technical abilities", "Hard skills", "Communication and interpersonal skills", "Leadership skills"],
        writeAnswer: "Communication and interpersonal skills",
      },
      {
        id: 55,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of mindfulness in personal development?",
        answers: ["To enhance focus and awareness", "To achieve physical fitness", "To improve financial management", "To create social connections"],
        writeAnswer: "To enhance focus and awareness",
      },
      {
        id: 56,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the concept of emotional intelligence?",
        answers: ["Ability to understand and manage emotions", "Ability to solve complex problems", "Ability to memorize vast amounts of information", "Ability to predict market trends"],
        writeAnswer: "Ability to understand and manage emotions",
      },
      {
        id: 57,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does the term 'personal branding' refer to?",
        answers: ["Marketing oneself as a product or service", "Creating logos and taglines", "Building physical products", "Developing corporate identities"],
        writeAnswer: "Marketing oneself as a product or service",
      },
      {
        id: 58,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the benefits of continuous learning in personal development?",
        answers: ["Improved adaptability", "Higher salary", "Greater job security", "Increased vacation time"],
        writeAnswer: "Improved adaptability",
      },
      {
        id: 59,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the importance of goal setting in personal development?",
        answers: ["Provides motivation and direction", "Reduces stress levels", "Increases leisure time", "Improves physical health"],
        writeAnswer: "Provides motivation and direction",
      },
      {
        id: 60,
        idQuiz:11,
        point: 2,
        question: "Which skill is considered essential for effective leadership?",
        answers: ["Decision-making", "Technical proficiency", "Conflict resolution", "Budget management"],
        writeAnswer: "Decision-making",
      },
      {
        id: 61,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of project management software?",
        answers: ["To track progress and allocate resources", "To create digital artwork", "To design web pages", "To edit videos"],
        writeAnswer: "To track progress and allocate resources",
      },
      {
        id: 62,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the role of time tracking tools in office productivity?",
        answers: ["To monitor hours spent on tasks", "To schedule meetings", "To calculate expenses", "To analyze market trends"],
        writeAnswer: "To monitor hours spent on tasks",
      },
      {
        id: 63,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the benefits of using cloud storage in office productivity?",
        answers: ["Accessibility from anywhere", "Reduction in electricity costs", "Enhanced physical security", "Improved employee morale"],
        writeAnswer: "Accessibility from anywhere",
      },
      {
        id: 64,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does the term 'task management' refer to in office productivity?",
        answers: ["Organizing and prioritizing tasks", "Creating financial reports", "Developing marketing strategies", "Building customer relationships"],
        writeAnswer: "Organizing and prioritizing tasks",
      },
      {
        id: 65,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the key features of collaborative software tools in office productivity?",
        answers: ["Real-time editing and commenting", "Data analysis and visualization", "Web design and development", "Video production and editing"],
        writeAnswer: "Real-time editing and commenting",
      },
      {
        id: 66,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "How does task automation improve office productivity?",
        answers: ["Reduces manual errors and saves time", "Increases paper consumption", "Expedites shipping and logistics", "Enhances customer service"],
        writeAnswer: "Reduces manual errors and saves time",
      },
      {
        id: 67,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of ergonomic office furniture in productivity?",
        answers: ["To enhance comfort and prevent injuries", "To reduce internet usage", "To improve financial management", "To optimize search engine rankings"],
        writeAnswer: "To enhance comfort and prevent injuries",
      },
      {
        id: 68,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the advantages of using productivity apps on mobile devices?",
        answers: ["Flexibility to work on the go", "Increased desktop computer usage", "Higher utility bills", "Greater reliance on physical storage"],
        writeAnswer: "Flexibility to work on the go",
      },
      {
        id: 69,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the benefits of continuous improvement initiatives in office productivity?",
        answers: ["Enhanced efficiency and effectiveness", "Decreased job satisfaction", "Increased operational costs", "Reduced software updates"],
        writeAnswer: "Enhanced efficiency and effectiveness",
      },
      {
        id: 70,
        idQuiz:13,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the role of digital communication tools in office productivity?",
        answers: ["Facilitating instant messaging and video conferencing", "Automating financial transactions", "Designing logos and banners", "Conducting market research"],
        writeAnswer: "Facilitating instant messaging and video conferencing",
      },
      {
        id: 71,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the purpose of performance appraisals in HR management?",
        answers: ["To assess employee job satisfaction", "To monitor internet usage", "To analyze financial statements", "To evaluate employee performance"],
        writeAnswer: "To evaluate employee performance",
      },
      {
        id: 72,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the key components of recruitment and selection in HR management?",
        answers: ["Job analysis, sourcing, and interviewing", "Budgeting, forecasting, and auditing", "Content creation and social media management", "Event planning and coordination"],
        writeAnswer: "Job analysis, sourcing, and interviewing",
      },
      {
        id: 73,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "How does training and development contribute to employee retention?",
        answers: ["By enhancing skills and knowledge", "By increasing website traffic", "By reducing inventory costs", "By improving legal compliance"],
        writeAnswer: "By enhancing skills and knowledge",
      },
      {
        id: 74,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the benefits of a diverse and inclusive workplace in HR management?",
        answers: ["Enhanced creativity and innovation", "Decreased customer satisfaction", "Increased office supply expenses", "Reduced employee turnover"],
        writeAnswer: "Enhanced creativity and innovation",
      },
      {
        id: 75,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "What does the term 'employee engagement' refer to in HR management?",
        answers: ["The emotional commitment of employees", "The volume of sales transactions", "The frequency of marketing campaigns", "The speed of website loading"],
        writeAnswer: "The emotional commitment of employees",
      },
      {
        id: 76,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "How does effective communication enhance HR management?",
        answers: ["By fostering teamwork and collaboration", "By increasing server capacity", "By optimizing supply chain logistics", "By automating financial reporting"],
        writeAnswer: "By fostering teamwork and collaboration",
      },
      {
        id: 77,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "What are the advantages of using HR analytics and metrics?",
        answers: ["To make data-driven decisions", "To reduce printer maintenance costs", "To streamline payment processing", "To enhance customer support services"],
        writeAnswer: "To make data-driven decisions",
      },
      {
        id: 78,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "What role does employee benefits play in HR management?",
        answers: ["To attract and retain talent", "To manage social media campaigns", "To improve search engine rankings", "To design promotional materials"],
        writeAnswer: "To attract and retain talent",
      },
      {
        id: 79,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "How does HR management contribute to organizational culture?",
        answers: ["By shaping values and norms", "By increasing email storage capacity", "By optimizing website performance", "By analyzing market trends"],
        writeAnswer: "By shaping values and norms",
      },
      {
        id: 80,
        idQuiz:14,
        point: 2,
        question: "What is the significance of HR policies and procedures?",
        answers: ["To ensure consistency and fairness", "To manage inventory levels", "To enhance graphic design", "To automate payroll processing"],
        writeAnswer: "To ensure consistency and fairness",
      },
  ];
  
  